Post, Libby; Papers apap045
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Libby Post Papers
1978-2005
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Post, Libby
apap045
4.18 cubic ft.
The Libby Post Papers contain political campaign documents, professional correspondences, news clippings, meeting minutes, agendas, document drafts, press releases, news letters, civil activism notes, and other materials that document her involvement securing various LGBT rights and with political organizations, as well as the general LGBT community in Albany, NY.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted with the exception of one folder in Series 5 noted in the container list.
Acquisition Information
Libby Post donated all items in this manuscript group to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, in May 1994, May 2003, December 2005, and June 2006.
Biographical Sketch
Libby Post has served as press secretary, campaign manager, and media coordinator for various politicians and organizations in New York State's Capital Region. Her academic credentials include an MA in political communications from the State University of New York at Albany. Post's political consulting and public relations firm, Communication Services,[1] has worked with a number of Democratic candidates in their quests for elected office. Post's work is a combination of her profession as media coordinator and her own political activism. Her early work as part of the Equal Rights Amendment (ERA) Working Group on the state level--a group within the ERA Task Force chaired by Democratic State Assemblywoman May W. Newburger--can be traced in the records back to 1982.
In political campaigns, Post served as Press Secretary for Assemblywoman May W. Newburger (Democrat--Great Neck); Press Secretary for the Ed Bloch campaigns against incumbent Republican Gerald B.H. Solomon from New York's 24th Congressional District; and as Press Secretary for Sheila Healy, 6th District Democratic candidate for the Albany County Legislature. Post has continued to work with Albany-area candidates, including Sharon Ward in her 6th Ward Democratic primary campaign and Nancy Burton's campaigns for City Comptroller in 1993 and 1997. Post worked extensively with Helen Desfosses in her 1997 and 2001 campaigns for City Council President. In 2002, Post helped organize fundraising with the Women for McCall-Mehiel group campaigning for Carl McCall during his run for New York State Governor.
In 1986, Post became Media Coordinator for Family Planning Advocates of New York State, Inc., which "lobbies on behalf of Planned Parenthood and other family planning groups." During her tenure as Media Coordinator for Family Planning Advocates of New York State, Inc., Post provided news coverage and press releases on behalf of the lobbying efforts of the group, and in 1987, she covered the 10 year anniversary conference celebrated by Family Planning Advocates of New York State. Also in 1987, Post became Press Secretary for the New York State Coalition Against Domestic Violence, Inc., providing press releases regarding the "Speak Out Rally" held in Albany, New York on March 9, 1987.
Post has also done a great deal of work with several Capital Region organizations promoting gay and lesbian rights. She served as co-chair of the Albany-based New York State Lesbian and Gay Lobby in 1989 and oversaw its merger in 1990 with FAIRPAC, a New York City based organization, to become the Empire State Pride Agenda. In 1994 she became a board member of the Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community Council (CDGLCC). She became president of CDGLCC (now referred to as the Capital Pride Center) in April 1999, and later served as president emeritus beginning in April 2004. Post continues to be active in the LGBT community, and currently contributes to a LGBT political blog on the Albany Times Union website.
1. Additional information about Community Services is available at http://www.commservices.net/csindex.html/.
Scope and Contents
The Libby Post Papers primarily hold Post's press releases created for politicians and political interest groups. Campaign materials for Ed Bloch's 1984 bid for Congress, document Bloch's record on various issues with editorial letters regarding his candidacy, voting records, and "Bloch For Congress" newsletters. Materials for Helen Desfosses' campaigns for city council president are extensive, covering most aspects of the campaign, including items from within the campaign such as planning documents and volunteer lists. The materials for Nancy Burton primarily document her actions during time as city comptroller between the 1993 and 1997 campaigns in news clippings and press releases. Campaign materials for Sheila Healy's bid for Albany County 6th District Legislator are limited to a campaign brochure and seven press releases publicizing Healy's political record. Materials for Carl McCall are limited to announcements and invitation lists for a fund raising breakfast. Sharon Ward's campaign materials for 1989 consist of a campaign plan for the 6th District Democratic primary.
Press releases for New York State Assemblywoman May W. Newburger that Post created as press secretary, outline Newburger's stand on public issues with quotes, voting records, and information on Newburger's activities. Also included are files of press coverage and news clippings discussing Newburger, not all of which were the result of Post's press releases. Post's role as media coordinator for Family Planning Advocates of New York State, Inc., is documented by press releases, press coverage, notes regarding the preparation of a conference, and an agenda for the organization's 10th anniversary celebration. Press releases for, and press coverage clippings regarding, the New York Coalition on Domestic Violence, highlight Post's role in the organization, especially her work with the "Speak Out Rally" held on March 9, 1987. Post's lobbyist work for the Equal Rights Amendment (ERA) is documented in notes of meetings and administrative materials of the ERA "Working Group", which lobbied for passage of the Amendment. The ERA files also include press coverage and press releases that trace the progress of ratification during this year. There are no records of Post's work for ERA before or after 1984.
The Subject Files that Libby Post collected on various issues relate to her work and public interests and include news clippings and informative literature on homosexuality, child abuse, Planned Parenthood (affiliated with Family Planning Advocates of New York State, Inc.), gay rights, legislative matters regarding reproduction, and state law. The fifth series consists of papers collected during Post's tenure as President of the Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community Council, 1999-2003. It includes documents relating to the running of the council, such as policy statements and financial paperwork, as well as public relations materials like event announcements and press releases. The final series contains correspondences, agendas, policies, meeting minutes, and other materials related to the Empire State Pride Agenda.
Arrangement of the Collection
All series are arranged chronologically. The collection is organized into the following series:
Women; Social Activists and Public Advocates; Public Servants; Human Sexuality and Gender Identity; Albany, New York; Gay rights--New York (State); Community organization--New York (State); Sexual minorities--New York (State); Equal rights amendments--United States; New York (State)--Politics and government; New York (State)--Social conditions; Clippings; Correspondence; Posters; Bylaws (administrative records); Photographs; Calendars; Brochures; Minutes; Newsletters; Bloch, Ed; Burton, Nancy; McCall, Carl; Desfosses, Helen; Healy, Sheila; Post, Libby; Ward, Sharon; Empire State Pride Agenda; Capital Pride Center
- Political Campaigns, 1984-2002; 1; 1.66 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series documents Libby Post's involvement with the political campaigns of six Democratic candidates: Ed Bloch, Sheila Healy, Nancy Burton, Helen Desfosses, Sharon Ward and Carl McCall.
  - Ed Bloch, 1984; 1.1
    Ed Bloch's 1984 campaign for Congress includes the press kit with endorsement letters, biographical information on the candidate, voting records of his opponent, press releases, campaign brochures, a series of "Bloch for NYS State Congress" newsletters, and news clippings regarding the election campaign.
    - New York State Congressional Campaign, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 1)
  - Sheila Healy, 1987; 1.2
    Sheila Healy's 1987 campaign for Albany County Legislator for the 6th district includes one campaign brochure and seven 1-page newsletters on constituent services and campaign issues.
    - 6th District Democrat Candidate-Albany County Legislature, 1987 (Box 1 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 2)
  - Nancy Burton, 1989-1997; 1.3
    Nancy Burton's 1993 and 1997 campaign for City Comptroller includes campaign plans as well as press releases and news clippings from Nancy Burton during her 1993-1997 term as Comptroller. Electronic copies of the 2001 campaign website are available upon request.
    - City Comptroller, 1989-1997 (Box 1 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 3-4)
  - Helen Desfosses, 1997-2001; 1.4
    Helen Desfosses' 1997 and 2001 City Council President campaigns include campaign plans, news clippings relating to the campaign, donor and volunteer lists, press releases, endorsement letters, petitions, and photographic contact sheets.
    - City Council President Campaign, Volunteer and Donor Lists, 1993-1997 (Box 1 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 5)
    - City Council President Campaign, Statement of Financial Disclosure, 1995; 1997 (Box 1 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 6)
    - City Council President Campaign, Endorsements, 1997 (Box 1 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 7)
    - City Council President Campaign, Fundraising, 1997 (Box 1 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 8)
    - City Council President Campaign, Fundraising Flyers, 1997 (Box 1 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 9-10)
    - City Council President Campaign, Fundraising Response, 1997 (Box 2 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 1)
    - City Council President Campaign, Meetings and Campaign Plans, 1997 (Box 2 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 2)
    - City Council President Campaign, Memos and Press Releases, 1997 (Box 2 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 3)
    - City Council President Campaign, News Clippings, 1997 (Box 2 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 4)
    - City Council President Campaign, Petitions, 1997 (Box 2 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 5)
    - City Council President Campaign, Planning, 1997 (Box 2 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 6)
    - City Council President Campaign, Theme and Message Literature, 1997 (Box 2 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 7)
    - City Council President Campaign, Contact Shoots, ca. 1997 (Box 2 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 8)
    - City Council President Campaign, 2001 (Box 2 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 9-11)
    - Campaign Sign, ca. 2001 (Oversized 1, Folder 1)
  - Sharon Ward, 1989; 1.5
    Sharon Ward's 1989 6th Ward City Council campaign contains the campaign plan for the Democratic primary.
    - 6th Ward Democratic Primary, 1989 June (Box 2 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 12)
  - Carl McCall, 2002; 1.6
    Carl McCall's 2002 campaign for New York Governor includes the announcements and invitation lists for a breakfast fundraiser with the Women for McCall-Mehiel organization.
    - New York Governor Campaign, Women for McCall-Mehiel, 2002 September (Box 2 (1-Political Campaigns), Folder 13)
- Media Coordinator/Press Secretary, 1984-1987; 2; 0.17 cubic ft.
  This series contains material relating to Libby Post's two positions as Press Secretary; for New York State Assemblywoman May W. Newburger and Family Planning Advocates of New York State, Inc. The folders on Newburger include 1984-1985 news clippings and 1985 press releases and related coverage. The folders on Family Planning Advocates of New York State, Inc. contain press releases prepared by Post, notes on preparing for a press conference, documentary material regarding a 10th anniversary celebration, and news clippings regarding the New York State Coalition on Domestic Violence "Speak Out Rally" in 1987.
  - May Newburger - New York State Assembly Woman Press Coverage, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Media Coordinator/Press Secretary), Folder 1)
  - Family Planning Advocates of New York State - Press Conference, 1985 November 14 (Box 1 (2-Media Coordinator/Press Secretary), Folder 2)
  - May Newburger - New York State Assembly Woman Press Coverage, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Media Coordinator/Press Secretary), Folder 3-4)
  - Family Planning Advocates of New York State - Press Releases, 1985-1986 (Box 1 (2-Media Coordinator/Press Secretary), Folder 5)
  - New York Coalition Against Domestic Violence - "Speak Out Rally" - Albany, NY, 1987 March 09 (Box 2 (2-Media Coordinator/Press Secretary), Folder 1)
  - New York Coalition Against Domestic Violence - Press Coverage, 1987 March 09-1987 March 10 (Box 2 (2-Media Coordinator/Press Secretary), Folder 2)
  - Family Planning Advocates of New York State 10th Anniversary Conference, 1987 (Box 2 (2-Media Coordinator/Press Secretary), Folder 3)
  - Family Planning Advocates of New York State - Press Releases, 1987; Undated (Box 2 (2-Media Coordinator/Press Secretary), Folder 4)
- Lobbyist Work for the Equal Rights Amendment, 1982; 1984; 3; 0.17 cubic ft.
  This series documents Libby Post's lobbyist work for the Equal Rights Amendment, and includes Post's handwritten notes from meetings of the ERA "Working Group", memos from May Newburger (as chairperson), studies and reports on the ERA, and statistics on support of groups and organizations. It also includes editorials on the ERA, news clippings of the NYS Assembly debate on, and the Senate rejection of, the ERA, notes from an ERA press conference, and the records of the press conference with then Democratic Governor Mario Cuomo regarding ERA.
  - Women's Action Alliance - NYC Area Mailing List, 1982 (Box 1 (3-Lobbyist Work for the Equal Rights Ame), Folder 1)
  - Assembly Debate, 1984 May 21 (Box 1 (3-Lobbyist Work for the Equal Rights Ame), Folder 2)
  - Press Conference, 1984 June 12 (Box 1 (3-Lobbyist Work for the Equal Rights Ame), Folder 3)
  - Senate Rejection-Press, 1984 June 12 (Box 1 (3-Lobbyist Work for the Equal Rights Ame), Folder 4)
  - Madeline Rochen's Op-Ed Piece, 1984 June 14 (Box 1 (3-Lobbyist Work for the Equal Rights Ame), Folder 5)
  - News Clippings - "Momentum Articles", 1984 June 19 (Box 1 (3-Lobbyist Work for the Equal Rights Ame), Folder 6)
  - Press Conference with Gov. Mario Cuomo, 1984 June 20 (Box 1 (3-Lobbyist Work for the Equal Rights Ame), Folder 7)
  - Commentary Clips by Reporters, 1984 (Box 1 (3-Lobbyist Work for the Equal Rights Ame), Folder 8)
  - Editorials, 1984 (Box 1 (3-Lobbyist Work for the Equal Rights Ame), Folder 9)
  - Press/Last Week of 1984 Session (Box 1 (3-Lobbyist Work for the Equal Rights Ame), Folder 10)
  - Working Group, 1984 (Box 1 (3-Lobbyist Work for the Equal Rights Ame), Folder 11)
- Subject Files, 1978-2003; Undated; 4; 1.58 cubic ft.
  This series predominantly contains newspapers and news clippings on subjects including homosexuality, child abuse, Planned Parenthood, gay rights, reproduction issues survey, and state law.
  - Buffalonian, Libby Post, Editor-in-Chief, 1978 (Oversized 2)
  - Child Abuse, 1985 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Planned Parenthood NY State Survey on Reproduction, 1985 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - News Clippings on Reproductive Issues, Organizations, Surveys, Legislation, 1985-1986 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Fund for Human Dignity, The First National Lesbian and Gay Education Conference, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Newspaper:Hardcopy: For the Common Good, 1989 March (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - News Clippings: Homosexuality and Women's Issues, 1989 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - San Francisco Sentinel 20th Anniversary Look at Stonewall, 1989 (Oversized 1, Folder 2)
  - Niagara County Notes, 1989; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Sappho's Isle Column, 1989-1992; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Lesbians and Gays for Cuomo, 1990; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Civil Rights, 1990-1991; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Sappho's Isle with Column by Libby Post, 1990-1992 (Oversized 2)
  - Lesbian/Gay Perspective Piece, 1991 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Metroland Profile of Jim Perry, 1991 (Oversized 1, Folder 3)
  - Troy: Sandvidge/PBA Flap, 1991 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Calendar Supplies, 1991-1993; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Newspaper:Craft Fair, 1992 May 31-1992 June 12 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - "The Bridge" Newsletter, 1992 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - "Storage Bedfellows" Article, Empire State Report, 1992 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - "Colorado Faces Rights Battle" and Letters to the Editor, 1992; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Shenedehowa High School Student Discrimination, 1999 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Healthy Capital District Initiative, 1999; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Promotions, 1999; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Roland Hollins Case, 2000-2001 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Statement of Client Rights, 2002 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Times Union Daily News Budget, 2002 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Capital Leadership, 2002-2003; Undated (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1-2)
  - "Badge of Courage" Newsletter, 2003 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - "Build a Better Board" Participant Workbook, 2003 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Boom Profile of Libby Post, 2004 (Oversized 1, Folder 4)
  - Development Plan, Undated (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Family Celebrations Wedding Catalog, Undated (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - "Inside Out" Pamphlet, Undated (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - New York State Lesbian and Gay Lobby Brochures, Undated (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Samples From Kendra Fantiff, Undated (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
- Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community Council, 1989-2005; Undated; 5; 0.99 cubic ft.
  This series contains documents produced during Libby Post's term as President of the Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community Council (CDGLCC) from April 1999-April 2004. It includes financial statements, internal correspondence, statements of official policy and procedure, publications, announcements and information about events such as Capital Pride and Empire State Pride Agenda Lobby Day. The agendas, minutes and reports presented from both CDGLCC board and committee meetings are found together in the Meetings, Agenda and Reports April, 2001-April 2003 folder. Much of the material from 2000 and earlier was organized into a three-ring binder and has been retained in its original order and categories.
  - Awards, 1988 (Box 1 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 1)
  - Lobby Day, Organizing Workshop, 1989 (Box 1 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 2)
  - Stonewall Coalition, 1989 (Box 1 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 3)
  - Binder, Grants, 1993-1999 (Box 1 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 4)
  - Financial Documents, 1994-1996; 1999-2000; 2002-2003; Undated (Box 1 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 5-7)
  - Binder, Rainbow Society, 1995-1999 (Box 1 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 8)
  - By-Laws, Policies, and Reports, 1996-1999; 2001-2003; Undated (Box 1 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 9)
  - Capital Pride (1-2 of 3), 1998-1999; 2001-2003; 2005 (Box 1 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 10-11)
  - Capital Pride (3 of 3), 1998-1999; 2001-2003; 2005 (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 1)
  - Correspondences and Memorandums, 1998-2003; 2005; Undated (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 2-3)
  - Binder, Legislation Reception, 1999 May 18 (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 4)
  - commUNITY, 1999 May-1999 August; 2001 December-2002 December (Oversized 1, Folder 5)
  - Board Orientation Session, 1999 (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 5)
  - Direct Mail, 1999 (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 6)
  - CDGLCC Board of Directors Manual, 1999; Undated (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 7)
  - CDGLCC Partners, 1999; Undated (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 8)
  - Binder, Grants, 1999-2000 (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 9)
  - Binder, United Airlines and SEFA and Linkages, 1999-2000 (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 10)
  - CommUnity News Journal, 1999-2000 (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 11)
  - GLSEN Documents, 1999-2000 (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 12)
  - Meeting Minutes, Agendas, and Reports, 1999-2001; 2003; Undated (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 13)
  - CDGLCC Publications and Announcements, 1999-2003 (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 14)
  - Notes From Retreats, 1999; 2001-2002; Undated (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 15)
  - CDGLCC Events, 1999-2000; 2002; 2004; Undated (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 16)
  - CDGLCC Financial Statements, 1999; 2001-2004 (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 17)
  - Community Health Issues Survey, 2000; Undated (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 18)
  - Binder, Youth Program and Scholarship, ca. 2000 (Box 2 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 19)
  - CDGLCC Nomination Process, 2001 (Box 3 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 1)
  - CDGLCC Financial Audit, 2001; 2002 (Box 3 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 2)
  - Phase 1: Capital Campaign Report, 2001-2002 (Box 3 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 3)
  - Rebranding Notes, 2001-2002; Undated (Box 3 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 4)
  - Employee Evaluations, 2001-2003; Undated (Box 3 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 5)
  - Empire State Pride Agenda Lobby Day, 2002 May (Box 3 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 6)
  - Corporate Calls, 2002 (Box 3 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 7)
  - D/B/A Certificate, 2002 (Box 3 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 8)
  - Donor Reception List, 2002 (Box 3 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 9)
  - Journal Ads, 2002 (Box 3 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 10)
  - Small Business Council Awards, 2002 (Box 3 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 11)
  - Executive Director Search - [RESTRICTED], 2002-2003; Undated (Box 3 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 12)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Must consult archivist before viewing this material.
  - Awards Dinner, 2002-2005 (Box 3 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 13)
  - Sonda Legislative Debate Transcript, 2003 January 30 (Box 3 (5-Capital District Gay and Lesbian Community ), Folder 14)
  - commUNITY, 2003 May-2003 December (Oversized 1, Folder 6)